{"Topic": "Andhra Pradesh", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Who of the following was associated with the Rampa Rebellion of 1922-24?", "op1": "Alluri Sitarama Raju", "op2": "Gottipatti Brahmaiah", "op3": "Pingali Venkayya", "op4": "Kalluri Chandramouli", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Kuchipudi, the village is located in which district of Andhra Pradesh?", "op1": "Guntur", "op2": "Krishna", "op3": "Nellore", "op4": "Anantapur", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following finds a place in the Ramsar List of wetlands of international importance?", "op1": "Pulicat lake", "op2": "Godavari river", "op3": "Kolleru lake", "op4": "Nellapattu sanctuary", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is famous for holding a Flamingo Festival every year?", "op1": "Pulicat lake", "op2": "Prakasam barrage", "op3": "Coringa sanctuary", "op4": "Kolleru lake", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Sriharikota, the site of Satish Dhawan Space Research Centre is located in which district?", "op1": "Chittoor", "op2": "Cuddapah", "op3": "Krishna", "op4": "Nellore", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a part of Union Territory located in Andhra Pradesh?", "op1": "Mahe", "op2": "Yanam", "op3": "Karaikal", "op4": "Daman", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following states does not share a boundary with Andhra Pradesh?", "op1": "Odisha", "op2": "Chhattisgarh", "op3": "Karnataka", "op4": "Madhya Pradesh", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the oldest university in the State?", "op1": "Andhra University", "op2": "Sri Venkateshwara University", "op3": "Acharya Nagarjuna University", "op4": "Krishna University", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following persons from Andhra Pradesh is credited with the design of the Indian National Flag?", "op1": "D Subba Rao", "op2": "Pingali Venkayya", "op3": "NG Ranga", "op4": "N Ramakrishna", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The well-known dancing couple Raja and Radha Reddy are associated with which dance form?", "op1": "Bharat Natyam", "op2": "Yakshagana", "op3": "Odissi", "op4": "Kuchipudi", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who was the first Telugu writer to be conferred the Jnanpith Award?", "op1": "C Narayan Reddy", "op2": "Ravuri Bharadwaja", "op3": "Viswanatha Satyanarayana", "op4": "UR Ananthamurthy", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "With which of the following performing art forms was Saraswati Bai associated?", "op1": "Hari Katha", "op2": "Kuchipudi", "op3": "Burra Katha", "op4": "Bharat Natyam", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who was the first Telugu writer to be conferred the Sahitya Akademi Award?", "op1": "C Narayan Reddy", "op2": "Suravaram Pratap Reddy", "op3": "Viswanatha Satyanarayana", "op4": "Gurram Joshua", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "With which of the following performing arts was Shri Shaik Nazar, recipient of Padma Shri and Sangeet Natak Akademi award associated?", "op1": "Burra Katha", "op2": "Hari Katha", "op3": "Andhranatyam", "op4": "Qawalli", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The critically endangered bird Jerdon\u2019s Courser can only be found at which of the following sanctuaries?", "op1": "Sri Lankamaleswara Wildlife Sanctuary", "op2": "Nellapattu Bird Sanctuary", "op3": "Coringa Wildlife Sanctuary", "op4": "Papikonda Wildlife Sanctuary", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the site of one of the 12 Jyotirlingas of Hindu religion in India?", "op1": "Tirupati", "op2": "Bhadrachalam", "op3": "Srisailam", "op4": "Tadipatri", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "How is Gona Vema Reddy better known as?", "op1": "Nannaya", "op2": "Pothana", "op3": "Tikanna", "op4": "Vemana", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following is the author of Andhra Maha Bhagvathamu which is a translation of Puranas from Sanskrit to Telugu?", "op1": "Nannaya", "op2": "Pothana", "op3": "Tikanna", "op4": "Vemana", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following is not a part of Kavitrayam, the trinity of poets who translated Mahabharata into Telugu?", "op1": "Nannaya", "op2": "Errana", "op3": "Tikanna", "op4": "Pothana", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following from Andhra Pradesh was the first Indian woman to win an individual medal in the Olympics?", "op1": "Karnam Malleshwari", "op2": "Saina Nehwal", "op3": "Sania Mirza", "op4": "PV Sindhu", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following from Andhra Pradesh is the youngest Indian female to become a chess grandmaster?", "op1": "D. Harika", "op2": "Koneru Humpy", "op3": "S Vijayalakshmi", "op4": "B Pratyusha", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "With which of the following instruments was U Srinivas, the famous music personality associated?", "op1": "Sitar", "op2": "Veena", "op3": "Mridangam", "op4": "Mandolin", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following was the capital of Andhra state from 1953 to 1956?", "op1": "Kurnool", "op2": "Nellore", "op3": "Cuddapah", "op4": "Visakhapatnam", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "How many MPs represent the State in the Indian Parliament?", "op1": "22", "op2": "25", "op3": "28", "op4": "32", "Answer": 2}]}